NABIL MOHAMMED

Software engineer | Gold medalist of Addis Ababa University



Bole woreda 08,Safary Academy Addis Ababa



11-01-2000



+251 966 686 856





SOCIAL MEDIA



http://linkedin.com/in/nabilmohd/



http://github.com/nabil-nablotech

PROFILE

I am a software engineer specialized in web technologies like REACT, Angular, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Bootstrap, C#, ASP.NET, JAVA, Spring-boot, MySQL, etc. I am an open minded person who can adopt new and different technologies to fulfill business needs. My hobby is playing video games. I enjoy playing action and open world games.

EDUCATION

2017 - October 2021

Addis Ababa University, Ethiopia, Addis Ababa

Bachelors in Information Systems (CGPA: 3.99)

2004 - 2017

Ethiopian International School, Saudi Arabia, Riyadh

KG 1 - Grade 12

EXPERIENCE

November 2021 - present

Perago Information System - Ethiopia, Addis Ababa

Front end developer

Responsibilities:

- Working on developing and implementing electronic government and B2B commerce solutions like e-SERVICES that is owned by the Ethiopian Ministry of Communication and Information Technology.
- Build user interfaces using Nextjs/React, TailwindCSS.
- Used tools like Git & Azure devops to push code and publish it using the CI/CD pipeline.

May 2021 - July 2021

Addis Ababa University - Ethiopia, Addis Ababa

Intern

Responsibilities:

• Develop a digital library system by customizing an open source software called Greenstone.

July 2019 - February 2020

Moka Foreign Overseas Recruitment Agency - Ethiopia, Addis Ababa

IT Support Technician

Responsibilities:

- Install, maintain and troubleshoot software and hardware of the computer systems of the company.
- Developed a simple desktop app called: Visa Number Barcode Generator that was required by the Saudi Arabian Embassy.

AWARDS

SOFTWARE SKILLS

✓ Gold medalist - Addis Ababa University (2021)
✓ Outstanding performance - Ministry of Science and Higher Azure devops
Education (2021)
Figma
✓ Certificate of Excellence - School of Information Science (2021)
MS Office tools

Adobe Photoshop



PERSONALITY

Communicative

Creativity

Problem solving

Punctuality

Organized

Analytical

English

LANGUAGES

Amharic

Arabic



HOBBY





Technology

Games